well well well looks like someone and
that someone's name is stress monster
101 fell for our little hot potato prank
at sahara welcome back to another
episode of hermitcraft and it's time to
leave her punishment here for her to
read and for some reason i'm not really
sure what has been going on over at
stress's base but there there are
mushrooms floating around this is really
weird this was a bit of a shock when i
came over here anyway let's not get
distracted what we need to do is write
down her punishment
hi stress looks like you got spudded
your punishment is this
wear the skin and resource pack i send
you for your next episode quack please
turn over if it gets too much you can
take it off any time after two minutes
in your episode because this is um yeah
well you know it it is it is a little
bit weird this one yeah because she has
to wear this skin and it's it's a little
bit strange
it's it is a little bit strange because
i've i've completely yeah she's a she's
a duck
she's a mallard duck all right she's got
to wear this skin and she's got to put
on a resource pack and this resource
pack is gonna make some noises that go a
little something like this
it's just it's gonna quack at random
intervals
which is why she's allowed to take it
off at any time anyway we've got to
crack on with today's episode and the
first thing we need to do is actually
head on over to sahara where we've got a
few more bits that we need to do
we started doing a lot of the concrete
that is necessary for stocking sahara
but the concrete machine needs a bit of
work
oh it's not just mine my walking noise
it's everyone's
i'm gonna take i'm gonna change my skin
back this is stress is punishment and
not mine there we go so what we're going
to do
is we're going to improve this thing
we're going to give it a glass top i
think that a big glass
dough not dome but a big glass cage on
the top will make it look like a
redstone brain kind of thing because of
the way this is built just to cover it
up a little bit to make it look i don't
know just a bit more at home so let's
pop into a time lapse and get this job
done
this was a proper architect project
because iskall did the crafting bit
mumbo did the
tnt bit and then i actually did a lot of
the work making the concrete and then
i've decorated it as well so it's a
project that's worked out pretty cool
and now i just want to meet up with
mumbo and discount and show them the
whole thing
check it out dudes i have made this look
oh a little bit neater it does look
pretty cool actually i mean i thought
for a second you were gonna say i made
this i was like that's what i thought
was
gonna come in
you made this
i made this just to put a bow on it this
is mine now
i gotta say though this looks absolutely
amazing on this i love what you did with
the yellow here
big old box i i wanted to like keep it
looking because it looks a little bit
like a brain like a redstone brain so i
just sort of put a glass glass cabinet
in it and then that's it and i've
actually i've actually been using this
machine and i've got to say a scale it's
um it doesn't work properly
well that's what i'm gonna say
it definitely doesn't work if you press
all the buttons like
oh gosh don't do that oh no
oh
okay
here's some information for the oh my
god
here's the information for the viewers
who did this the other day and he broke
the machine i had to rebuild the the the
clock nice dude oh hold on i'm gonna
take care of this i gotta take care of
this first i just wanna ask what are you
gonna do with all this stuff that you've
just spat out uh have have you actually
throw it on the floor
and have it any concrete check it out
i've actually made a bunch of concrete
though
using the machine
oh my god this is actually impressive
so the machine is working yeah we can
totally stop working we can stop what
i've made here
yeah absolutely we we should however
take a pretty big price because if you
think about it there's a lot of sand and
gravel in these
yeah even though we have a fantastic
season so long but we can't under charge
for this seriously no
no
no i agree two diamonds per stack
minimum yeah that's still a good price
because that is the least yeah there's
two stacks of sand two stacks of gravel
the work and the dies we should take
this to the meeting room anyway yep yep
yeah okay
do you appreciate the fact that i've put
in
loads of these entrances and exits here
everywhere so you can just fly yeah so
you can fly in and out yeah that's smart
yeah
there should be no more roofs
no yeah just remove all the roof we
don't need them well i've i've just
before we start this meeting i just want
to take time to appreciate how beautiful
it is in here all of a sudden yeah i
wonder who did that
is this is this girl the average sahara
customer
someone with a mustache
yes dude i was i was sitting here for
like an hour trying to position the
position that black tie
mumbo mumbo is the average sahara
customer that's amazing
absolutely and oh have you noticed i've
got i've got a nice new chair too
where's your button get get back on your
button you've still got you're still
relegated
no no the buttons there well i don't
know if you remember i put it i put it
back on top of your chair
that's my chair you can sit there i
didn't like it when you were sitting up
there
yeah yeah yeah have you guys had a
little look at the uh
agreement membership yeah yeah no before
we get on to this actually yeah um back
onto my chair
can you make sure that my chair is
decommissioned i i can't remember if i
decommissioned it you just have to give
it a press
decommissioned
yeah i need to make sure i deactivated
my chair there's a yeah
whoa oh
oh for goodness oh really
i'll see you later boys i i i don't
really fancy talking about the sahara
now memberships i'm going to be totally
honest with you um so i'll catch you
i'll catch you in the next meeting boys
uh it's been nice
i can't believe i did that
he's still going
never mind that i just cleaned up and
fixed the conference room no wonder he's
yeah he literally just said he had no
more roofs he was
he was having a son he's still going see
yes i can't believe he broke sahara just
to get out of talking about his
let's be honest we all we all know that
he's lost
he and he sold two and one of them was
to himself
you know
oh no you did i did i did i sold one
more than you
to be fair to be fair with the last
voice that i have with this cold illness
i will say
you deserve it with that blimp
what do i win i don't know
i was thinking about that earlier yeah
we haven't really set any price or
anything that is crazy
and it destroyed the room just
broke everything what did you
do he he put a piston behind this
oh that's what that was okay i did
notice the piston earlier
well we've made an insane amount of
diamonds if we actually pop all these
together yeah
that is what
100 diamonds right there i feel like we
need to show these off like our vault is
too hidden over there we should like put
this out in the open maybe outside the
front of the shop and just say like yo
yo yo yo we got so many diamonds oh yeah
dragon rights i like that i like that we
are definitely better than concord now
yep diamonds wise so yeah 100
iscal you want to you want to find a
nice location for us to plant all of our
diamonds and show off especially oh is
there a way to make it just so that scar
can see it from cherry
i don't know
we have to make it tall enough so that
scar can see
i love that we've not made over a
thousand diamonds and the the media
finger that goes into your head is let's
show it off
because that's the point what's the
point of the diamonds unfortunately this
is uh sahara land out here and i'm i'm
thinking that this is actually the best
place for it so i think we're gonna have
to take this down in the sahara gardens
and make this our diamond vault what do
you think yeah i like it i mean this
this was only here for opening up so i'm
gonna start chopping it down this was
here for opening sahara and sahara is
open i'm sorry so we don't need a tent
anymore no i feel bad sorry sorry
did you kill the cow yeah
i'm sorry i'm sorry false but we we need
this land we need our garden back
we can take out all the dispensers as
well they look kind of weird yeah this
has been a neglected part of everything
for a while
so here's a little time lapse of myself
and iskall putting together the big
diamond case and i'll be honest we cheat
a little bit but i think it looks pretty
cool this is to show off and show
everybody particularly good times with
scar how many diamonds we've got and i
think that's pretty cool
i just started recording it and i'm
genuinely stuck
i don't know what's happened look at
this
help
why does this always happen to me
what is going on i'm stuck in fly mode i
should probably just wait for someone to
come and find me but
this is so strange can i even fly
this is oh oh oh there we go okay right
we're off so that's quite a lot of the
chores we had out of the way look at
this we have got one big pile of
diamonds to show off hi impulse uh check
it out we got ourselves a pile of
diamonds sahara is officially rich but
not that rich you might have seen if you
looked closely at the uh time lapse that
um let's just make sure that impulse
isn't watching i don't know where he's
gone but if we go inside
you'll see that there's um there's a
little bit of bamboozling and trickery
going on
it's um it's yeah it's it's completely
hollow on the inside uh maybe one day we
will fill these full of diamond blocks
but for now i think we're gonna have to
just let people believe
that this is uh legitimate because at
the moment it's hollow i think what we
should do is actually make a little
secret room in there i think we should
have like a secret hideout to to hang
out in just the architect guys but
imagine this when we get even more
diamonds this will become even more full
and impressive
so this is a big hey everyone sahara has
made some diamonds at last we officially
broke even and then made some profit
check it out
but that's not the only thing that we
need to do today we actually have a few
other things to do
the biggest of which
is to found my new event this is going
to be
amazing
so i just need to choose a spot to make
it before i explain exactly how this is
gonna work and i've got to admit the
shopping district is getting pretty full
it's not easy to slot anything in in
terms of build anymore
i don't actually need that much space
for it it's not particularly big this is
just somewhere to sign up
however i do need it to stand out
since this is an event maybe i'll go and
find somewhere in hermit land to make
this
what on earth
someone's made it ah the jingler jingle
land i don't think so
i don't think so baby ice the
the renaming of all the shops now that's
uh not very
original
i think the jingle is just more annoying
than anything else at this point so
let's find a nice
place oh i thought that was me okay just
hadn't loaded in i thought i was just
floating there okay right there's a
clear space here right next to dig
straight down
let's build it right here and not even
have two thoughts about it so
what is this new hermit event this is a
game for everyone and anyone to get
involved in it's gonna be awesome okay
so this game is called demise
and the game is actually pretty simple
but
it's going to take a few months to play
out
so i'm going to do a little bit of an
explanation of this game instead of just
talking at you like this i'm going to
explain it with a bit more of an
infographic and explain the rules of the
game
the goal of the game is simple you need
to be the last hermit alive now everyone
automatically starts off alive and they
go about their daily hermitcraft
business
eventually someone will die whether by
accident or not who knows and when you
die you have officially lost the game
and you are out and you have to change
your skin to be monochrome so that
everybody knows that you are dead
however the game isn't over for you you
are now on the dead team and it is your
job to
help the other lively hermits to join
your team
and you can do this by laying traps
and definitely not pvp
once those people have died they are
then also on the dead team and they can
help everyone else to join your team as
well eventually everybody ends up on the
dead team and has to work together to
get the last few people that are alive
this is the ultimate game of cat and
mouse and it's going to be a lot of fun
so now that you understand the game i
think we can all agree that this is
going to be extremely extremely fun but
i now need to make the sign up area and
it's actually not going to be that
complicated i just want to kind of make
a big skull here so it shouldn't be too
oh wait skulls are actually really tough
to build i'm not gonna lie skulls are
actually really difficult unless i go
for like pixel art this is gonna be
tough unless unless i don't go for a
skull i go for more like a skeleton hand
that might that might actually be easier
copying out of it because skulls skulls
are really tough
so here's the sign up chest this is
going to be super simple
and then all i've got to do is make some
spooky skeletal fingers that go over the
top of this board
and that should
make it nice and spooky and themed
around this whole this whole thing to be
honest with you this is literally just
the list of who's signing up so really
it's really like not that important it's
not going to affect anything this is
just to get people to try and sign up
and we'll see what happens from there
turns out hands are actually pretty
difficult to build as well
yeah just anything like building a human
or organic that's like meant to look
right instead of just you know minecraft
because building a minecraft character
is pretty easy but actually building a
real hand
not so easy not so easy
it's definitely not the most beautiful
hand in the entire world i um i
genuinely have tried to make this look a
bit more
realistic but it's uh
yeah it's it's not been easy actually um
i've really really been trying to make
this work uh so i think this might have
to do either way i don't want to take up
too much space here in hermit land i
just want to get people's attention and
this should do that
this should do that i mean even if
people go what the heck is that oh wait
is that a hand oh it'll still have
worked
now i just need to do the actual admin
part of this game and get people to sign
up so all we need now is a quick lectern
and then make this area look a little
bit better i think i now have like three
bases where i can get items from and i
still have to come over to hippie land
to get stuff
and this game has come just in time for
halloween
although i think this game will actually
last much longer than halloween it's
still pretty cool nonetheless that it's
come just in time for october which is
often referred to as spooktober okay
that took an awful long time to write
but i'm going to take you through anyway
new hermit event starts the 15th of
october noon gmt i have to do that
because you might die before or after or
whatever you need to know exactly when
it starts this game is called demise
this is a new game where the goal is
simple as you guys know don't die pay 50
diamonds add your name to the list and
then proceed to live as long as you can
in minecraft there's a catch though if
you die you lose but you are not out of
the game if you die you join the dead
team and must change your skin to be
monotone or dead your new goal as part
of the dead squad is simple you must
help the people who are still alive to
not live anymore however there is no pvp
allowed so you must think of another way
trapped to help the alive folk
everything else is up to you some final
points this game is dangerous and you
may lose your items you must be okay
with this when you sign up i do not want
to see anybody getting angry because a
trap accidentally or intentionally
got some items rid you need to be okay
with that when you sign up which is why
you also have this
god armor which is what all of us are
wearing in in the game that's uh that's
this stuff is god arm look how many um
enchantments there are on this you can't
do this anymore
so this is um this is really unfair
armor
um but the point is the god armor makes
this game too difficult and unreliable
etc so when you sign up please take some
armor from the chests provided you can
enchant them in any way you please so
basically you can't wear your god armor
you've got to wear either iron gold or
leather it's up to you if you die to a
bug the death does not count everyone
starts alive the dead may team up if
they want to the alive may team up if
they want to go about your business as
usual if you die when you are not
recording record a funny rendition of it
to show in your video good luck and stay
alive and if i've forgotten something
i'll i'll add it later this is you know
it's quite a it's quite a long book so
here we go we'll pop that down there now
i need to actually set up a bunch of
chests with some armor in which i
actually did not think about at all man
this is going to be good i need a i got
my fresh book for names all right so all
we got to do is craft up a bunch of the
gold stuff
and then that's pretty much the game
complete and then in three days time it
will begin whether people are ready or
not
and hopefully we can get most of the
hermits to sign up before then but they
can't sign up too long after it starts
once it starts it starts and that's it
so we'll have to make sure people sign
as much as possible
i may have made
i think i made one too many gold boots
i'm officially the first one to sign up
and just because it's my game doesn't
mean that i don't have to pay
so here i go
i've signed up there's my 50 diamonds
that is the prize pool for this game
and demise is officially open for
well for everything so i've got to get
rid of my i've got to get rid of my
armor and it's time to start being very
very careful now i'm going to opt in for
the gold because i think it's hilarious
i'm only gonna need that stuff and then
i need to get this stuff enchanted right
away oh my god this is gonna be a
different look to get used to this is
what i'm gonna be like while i'm still
alive in the game of demise although it
doesn't really matter if i die now
because the game remember the game
doesn't start until then so even if i
die now not a big deal so i don't have
to actually put this on until then
however as soon as it hits october 15th
the game begins and then we have to keep
a lookout for anybody that dies in the
game so hopefully we can get every
single hermit to sign up so i might as
well actually go straight back over to
the shopping district and get this armor
enchanted out the wazoo so i'll be ready
excuse me i mean that's perfect for that
if you could just like fly around here
circle this that would be awesome
and also i'd like to hear in the
comments who do you think will be the
first hermit to go
i think it's gonna be scar or mumbo not
sure who but i think i think i'll put my
diamonds on scar for this one
he does have the most deaths in the game
so far so now that we're here let's go
and pick up some books to make this
happen and it is done i think we should
probably get used to this new armor
although we've got a few days to prepare
ourselves for this challenge i actually
want to see how easy it is to actually
die because i'll need to be very very
careful
oh just a
tiny bit of flying damage really really
hurt
basically everyone's gonna live in fear
of this game for a little while i bet
even flying down this tunnel becomes
difficult because if you just hit
yourself once yep
uh
yeah
now now we know i'm not i'm not on the
dead team i was just testing the armor
the game hasn't started yet it's not
starting for a few days um but now i
know now i know this is not going to be
easy i think quite a lot of people will
die
quite quickly everyone will have to be
careful can i change my vote to to me to
die first
this is going to be a lot of fun well
that is actually it for today's video we
did a lot of stuff we have made this we
have had a meeting we have shown off our
diamonds and more importantly we have
just set up the coolest game
in hermitcraft history so well actually
i i can't say that uh we set up a cool
game so thank you very much for watching
i hope you enjoyed this episode and do
let me know what you think of the game
in the comments down below and who you
think will make it all the way to the
end and who's going to die first thank
you very much for watching and good bye
boy i need to get my stuff back now
i need an ender chest all right my stuff
doesn't despawn